Cody Griffith

Mathematical Research Scientist Santa Cruz, California 669-204-6374 (cell) · cody.griffith94@gmail.com

Career Objectives:

After about a decade of honing my applied mathematics, I have developed the tools, experience and programming knowledge to make myself useful to any field of analysis. I am a research scientist in mass spectrometry where I specialize in developing algorithms and apps for internal use as well as for customer-grade products. My hope is to continue to broaden my skill set and work towards making a positive impact both at the industry/research level but also towards social good.

Work Experience:

Research Scientist, 908 Devices California, USA December 2018 - Present

- Wrote succinct and clean code in Python and Matlab, cross-communicated between the two when necessary
- Spearheaded business UI/UX development by working with customers directly
- Acted as algorithm lead for user-facing proteomics software
- Worked in scrum-based software development cycles

Research Scientist, Data Science for Social Good (UBC) Vancouver, Canada May 2018 - September 2018

- Lead development of an R-Shiny application to view and analyze spatial/census data
- Collaborated with teams at Microsoft Vancouver and the city of Surrey
- Built a repository for future development and later years of DSSG to expand upon

Education:

2016-2018 University of British Columbia

Master of Science in Applied Mathematics Thesis- Non-Smooth Dynamics in the Stommel Model for Oceanic Circulation

2012-2016 Metropolitan State University of Denver

Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics

Academic Projects:

- Formed the basis of analysis on a two-dimensional dynamical system with strange bifurcating behavior.
- Partnered with Data Science for Social Good to create a central database and analysis platform for childhood vulnerabilities throughout the city of Surrey, British Columbia.
- Developed a method of analysis on a Dual-Capacity Stochastic Queue. Then, presented this work at the 2015 MAA regional conference in Colorado Springs as well as at the Undergraduate Research Conference in Denver.
- Partnered with Groundwork Denver for spatial & temporal analysis of E. Coli models in a local river

Dr. Robert Green

Algorithms lead 908 Devices bareen@908devices.com

Direct supervisor

Dr. Rachel Kuske

Chair of Mathematics Georgia Technical University Rachel@math.gatech.edu

Master's thesis advisor

Dr. Kevin Lin

DSSG Director **UBC** Kevin.lin@ubc.ca

Supervisor at DSSG

Dr. Elizabeth Ribble

Chair of Mathematics MSU Denver emcclel3@msudenver.edu

Undergraduate advisor